## ISOKEN ASEMOTA

- Calgary Canada Cell: 587-583-3143 Email: isokenasemota@vahoo.com
  - Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/isoken-helen-asemota/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/isoken-helen-asemota/</a>

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An innovative Relationship Manager with 9 + years of experience in personal and commercial accounts management. Experienced in business development, financial statement analysis, credit writing, credit report assessment, credit presentation skills, cash management services, and a skilled communicator in eliciting client information to tailor offerings to customers' needs. A successful entrepreneur running a personal business. Skillful with emerging communication and technology.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Account Manager, Small Business**

June 2022 - Present

Scotiabank, Calgary

- Maintain a portfolio of 300 high-value business owners through effective relationship and account management, leading to a 20% growth in the portfolio.
- Generated over 100 new businesses and referrals by developing partnerships with various Centres of Influence, internal and external partners and community leaders.
- Developed new onboarding processes by eliminating redundant and non-essential processes, which improved client engagement by 30%.
- Deliver value-add financial advice to customers throughout their business lifecycle and achieved 100% portfolio retention by identifying opportunities and addressing financial objectives.

#### **Business Owner**

Dec 2019 - July 2022

CIK Strength, Calgary

- Ran an e-commerce business specializing in creating fitness accessories to help professional women achieve their fitness goals with annual revenue of \$50,000 in 2021.
- Attended over 20 various exhibitions and other events to present the products and company to potential clients, partners and investors.
- Increased clientele by 25% in 2021 through a 3 part competitive marketing strategy.
- Streamlined service offering by surveying 100 clients, gathering feedback, and implementing changes which increased customer satisfaction by 20%.

# Relationship Manager, Commercial Banking

Feb 2020 - March 2021

ATB FINANCIAL, Calgary

- Managed a diverse portfolio of small business customers with assets up to \$15 million (CAD) by assessing the customers' business profile, and credit portfolio and delivering value-added financial advice and solutions to maintain the portfolio's overall health resulting in a 25% growth in sales revenue.
- Structured over 300 lending and financing requests up to a limit of \$500,000 by analyzing the customers' financial statements, creditworthiness, income, and overall situation to proffer solutions and advice resulting in a 20% portfolio loan growth.
- Oversaw the business activities of 2 branches in downtown Calgary and provided business support to branch partners which led to a 15% increase in the branch's revenue. Also performed face-to-face customer meetings and visited customers' business locations to learn about their business operations.
- Generated over 100 new businesses and proactively developed and maintained the growth of
  existing customers by leveraging centres of influence, strong negotiating and influencing.

## **Business Banking Advisor**

Dec 2018 - Feb 2020

ATB FINANCIAL, Calgary

• Examined, evaluated, and processed 500 loan applications by analyzing the credit history, financial statements, income, risk management policies, and overall financial situation of customers to make sound recommendations to meet their needs.

- Established and maintained strong relationships with individuals and small business
  customers resulting in a 20% increase in new business acquisitions. Network within
  the community and virtually to find and attract new business.
- Educated over 1000 customers on business products and services and proposed solutions tailored to their needs. Met sales targets and nurtured relationships with existing customers while onboarding over 500 new customers.
- Demonstrated excellent interpersonal and communication skills by connecting with customers virtually (phone and email) to learn more about the customer and their business and met established targets by resolving customers' inquiries and concerns promptly.

### Personal Banking Specialist, Retail Banking

Jul 2015 – Nov 2018

ATB FINANCIAL, Calgary

- Analyzed customers' financial status, credit risk assessment, and property evaluations to underwrite and present loans for credit approval which led to a 15% decrease in loan delinquency.
- Educated over 15,000 customers on how personal banking products and solutions work by explaining the features and benefits of products and services and ensuring customers have access to online and mobile banking tools.
- Proven track record of exceeding set targets and made over \$1.5 million in sales in 2017 by completing over 400 account orders received through the digital account opening platform and over 100 units obtained by assisting customers over the phone.
- Mentored and trained 25 junior and new team members.

### **MasterCard Service Specialist**

Jun 2014 – Jul 2015

ATB FINANCIAL, Calgary

Demonstrated problem-solving skills and strong organizational skills by personalizing every
interaction and proactively identifying and recommending solutions tailored to clients'
needs which led to a 15% increase in customer satisfaction. Also, fostered ongoing
customer-focused relationships by keeping records of customer interactions, recording
details of inquiries, complaints, or comments as well as actions taken.

### **Technical Support Representative**

Jan 2014 – Jun 2014

SHAW CABLE, Calgary

 Increased customer satisfaction by 25% by recommending ways for customers to alter product usage and delivering information about issues related to services that may cause disruptions and displayed organizational skills by planning, coordinating, and scheduling the installation of services at customers' homes.

### **EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT**

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals	2022
Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals	2022
Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC)	2021
Six Sigma Yellow Belt	2021
Business Administration Post Graduate Diploma (International Management) North Island College, British Columbia	2013
B.Sc Accounting Covenant University, Nigeria	2010

### VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

**Fashion Stylist** 

*Nov 2021 – Present* 

Making Changes Association / Dress for Success

• Provides fashion consultations to women looking to return to the workforce, providing advice on corporate outfits for interviews and general employment attire work.